Maximus Lewis

Aspiring Software Engineer looking to make a difference by creating impact. Lockport, Illinois, US | +1 (815) 708-4410 | mlew3223@gmail.com https://github.com/mslew | https://www.linkedin.com/in/maximuslewis/ | https://maximuslewis.com/

Computer Science Graduate

I am a recent computer science graduate with substantial hands-on experience with Python, Java, and JavaScript. Perceptive problem solver with an innate ability to learn quickly and apply previous experience with original solutions to solve problems.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Lewis University, August 2019 - May 2023 GPA: 3.82/4.0 (magna cum laude)

- Dean's List: all four years.
- Outstanding Student Employee of the ECaMS Department for the 2022-2023 school year.
- Dr. Stephany Schlachter Excellence in Undergraduate Scholarship Award Finalist.

PROJECTS

QuizMaster, Spring 2023

(https://github.com/QuizMasterInc/QuizMaster) | Software Systems Capstone Project at Lewis University

- Designed, as part of an Agile Scrum team, a comprehensive quizzing application to keep users' minds sharp on various topics.
- Redesigned and modernized the front-end application from HTML/CSS/JavaScript to React and Tailwind CSS optimizing the user experience.
- Onboarded and mentored Juniors to develop new features and take over maintenance ensuring project continuity.
- Technologies: React, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, Google Firebase, Google Cloud Functions.

In Theaters, Spring 2022

(https://github.com/mslew/in-theaters) | Mobile Application Development Final Project

- Built an Android application for users to see new movies in theaters that week.
- Designed the application to display information about the movie, resulting in an experience that allows users to browse any new movies and gauge their self-interest.
- Integrated Google services for ticket purchases, providing a holistic movie experience.
- Technologies: Android Studio, Java, IMDb API.

An Agent-Based Model of Environmental Transmission of *Clostridioides difficile* in Healthcare Settings, Summer 2022 – Summer 2023 | Mathematics Research Project

- Headed a team for the development of an AgentBased model that tracks infections of Clostridioides difficile.
- Forthcoming publication in the Journal of Mathematical Biology, 2024.
- Technologies: NetLogo.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- Proficient: Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, NetLogo.
- Working knowledge: Go, PHP, Assembly.

Technologies

React, Node.js, Express.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap 5, Sass, Svelte, Microsoft Azure, Google Firebase.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Will County School District 92 | Building Custodian August 2018 - Present | Lockport, IL

- Maintained building cleanliness per district standards for an assigned 8 classrooms.
- Collaborated with 25+ staff members to establish well-running classes and school events.

Lewis University | ECaMS Tutor

August 2022 - May 2023 | Romeoville, IL

- Advised 30+ students in Computer Science and Mathematics.
- Collaborated with 6+ professors and 7 tutors to better aid students.

AWARDS AND ACCOLADES

MAA Mathfest, 2022 | Janet L. Andersen Award for Undergraduate Research & The Annual Meeting of the Illinois Section of the MAA, 2023 | Outstanding Undergraduate Research

- Recognized for creating an advanced Agent-Based model to monitor Clostridioides difficile infections in a hospital setting.
- Technologies: NetLogo.